# **Chester Burbidge**

Web chester.codes
Github chestercodes

## **Profile**

A software professional with a passion for the craft, constantly learning and improving. Experienced with various methodologies across the full software development lifecycle. I have written code for mobile, the desktop and the full web stack, using a variety of programming languages and paradigms. A regular attender, and occasional presenter, of technical talks on various topics. Interested in teaching through volunteering my time to the Code Club initiative.

#### **Skills**

**Back End** - AKKA.NET, Apache Spark, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET WebForms, Azure Data Factory, Azure SQL, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure HdInsights, AWS DynamoDB, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, AWS Kinesis, AWS Redshift, AWS SQS, AWS S3, C++, C#, .NET Core, .NET Framework, Entity Framework, EF Core, F#, LINQ, neo4j, node.js, python, SAFE Stack, T-SQL, VB.NET

**Devops** - Azure Container Registry, Azure Resource Manager, AWS Cloudformation, AWS ECR, AWS ECS, AWS Opsworks, bash scripting, Cake, Chef, Continuous integration, Docker, git, Octopus Deploy, Packer, Powershell, terraform, TeamCity, Windows Containers

**Front End** - Angular Js, Bootstrap, CSS, D3, ES6 Promises, Elmish, Fable, GatsbyJS, GraphQL, grunt, HTML, javascript, jQuery, KnockoutJs, LESS, react.js, SAFE Stack, Typescript

Other - Azure Devops, Apache Cordova (Phone Gap), Ionic framework, JIRA, LaTeX, Resharper, RESTFul webservices, R, Source safe, SQL Server Management Studio, TFS, Visual studio, XSLT, XML

Testing - jasmine, karma, MoQ, MSTest, NUnit, Puppeteer, SpecFlow, VSTest, xUnit

## **Experience**

# **Parmenion** - Software Developer (contract, 3 extensions)

2018 - 2020 (1y, 7m)

- Extension of D2C services of investment platform and maintenence of existing legacy systems, including most Microsoft technologies of the last 10 years.
- Part of small group that led the migration of  $\sim$ 70 .Net framework and core services to windows containers.
- Developed internal tools, mostly in own time, for speeding up local development processes and project dependency analysis.

## **Scott Logic** - *Software Engineer*

2017 - 2018 (11m)

- Designed and implemented ETL pipeline on Azure using Data Factory V2. Implemented data warehouse reporting solution using SQL Datawarehouse and PowerBI.
- Wrote AWS infrastructure code for data engineering project using Terraform. Deployed a wide range of resources such as Kinesis, EC2 VMs and ECS containers.
- Developed REST API for automated download and analysis of github repositories using .Net Core running F# on ubuntu.
- Introduced SpecFlow into project to increase efficiency of test development and provide living documentation of automated tests.
- Ran internal study group for advancing company knowledge on cloud computing.

# **Abide Financial** - Software Engineer

2015 - 2017 (2y, 7m)

- Developed code to enrich and validate financial transaction data using C# and T-SQL, using 'best practices' and TDD where possible.
- Developed AWS lambda functions using python and node.js for environment automation. Tasks including database setup and automated resource spin up/down.
- Implemented CI and deployment solutions for AWS resources including EC2 and Lambda. This required extensive use of Teamcity and Octopus deploy.
- Created NuGet packages to promote 'best practices' in build and deployment automation.
- Wrote Powershell scripts for file archival and other Windows Server administration tasks. Automated configuration of log aggregation agents on production systems.
- Spread 'best practices' in methods and technologies through organising department wide, weekly workshops.

### **FundsLibrary** - Junior Developer

2014 - 2015 (*Iy*)

Maintained the Fundslibrary website in an agile environment. Practiced modern software development practices including TDD, CI and SOLID practices. Backend development involved C#, ASP.NET MVC and SQL Server to create web services and sites. Client side development used typescript, LESS and libraries such as KnockoutJs and jQuery.

#### **Toplevel Computing -** *Graduate Developer*

2013 - 2014 (1v)

Maintained proprietary web development product and extended behaviour to customer specifications. Role involved writing specications, designs and performing the implementation of code changes.

# **Education**

The University of Exeter 2010 - 2012

Phd Physics: The electrical properties of cell

Degree Not Attained

membranes

The University of Exeter 2007 - 2010

BSc. (Hons.) Mathematics and Physics 2:1

Queen Mary's College 2005 - 2007

A Levels Mathematics (A), Physics (B), Electronics (B), BTEC Music Practice (Distinction). AS Level:

**Further Mathematics AS (C)**